You can kind of
imagine this, right?
You can see it.
I've frozen the top
because of cooling rate.
It's right here.
I just cooled the top faster.
The inside isn't cold yet.
It starts to cool, and
it tries to solidify
at a different volume.
It pulls it in.
But see, that changes
the mechanical properties
of the surface.
That's called tempering.
That's called tempered glass.
This is tempered glass, and
there is no better example
of temporal glass than the
Prince Rupert's drop, which is
the demo that Peter has come.
Here's Peter.
There's Peter
blowing some glass.
This is what he does
in his free time.
He just throws these big
glass-bowling parties.
He also happens to be the
director of the glass lab,
like I said.
He also teaches the classes,
the glass-blowing classes.
There's one for
freshmen during IAP,
and there's another
one in the spring.
They're very popular.
But because you're in
3091, he'll get you in.
He doesn't like it when I say
that because it's not true.
[LAUGHTER]
But come talk to him.
He's right here, and I think
you've got a demo for us.
So I'm going to let
Peter take the stage
and show you the best example
of tempered glass you can do.
And if you want to use the mic--
if you want to talk.
--a little kit out